Ratchapol Marmongkol

Github: github.com/mratchapol Email: ratchapolhappy@gmail.com

Mobile: +66 888712331 Address: Lak Si, Bangkok



SUMMARY

Equipped with German Language Major, Computer Science Minor, plus experience in Master's in Computer Science, I have passion to start career in IT field. I am highly adaptable and do not stop improving myself. I seek a position where I can utilize my programming and/or foreign language skills.

EDUCATION

Master of Computer Science

2022 - 2024

Thammasat University; GPA: 3.33; In Progress (All coursework completed)

Bachelor in Liberal Arts, German Language

2018 - 2021

Thammasat University; GPA: 3.34

Triam Udom Suksa School

2015 - 2017

English-German program

SKILLS

Languages

Java 🚉 , Python, SQL (confident) | HTML, CSS, C++, JavaScript

- Strong understanding of principles of OOP
- Good understanding of Collections framework and basic data structure
- Good understanding of SQL
- Good understanding of Maven, Spring Boot annotations that handle REST API, dependency injection, and basic exceptions

Frameworks

Spring Boot Ospring , Pandas, NumPy, Scikit-Learn

Tools

MySQL, PostgreSQL, Git Eclipse, NetBeans, AWS

Platforms

- ETL data pipeline using AWS EC2, S3, Cloud9, Glue,

Athena, and QuickSight

Other skills

Reading Java Doc skill, Unix Command, Adaptability

English TOEIC 795, German Goethe-Zertifikat B1, Japanese JLPT N5

WORK EXPERIENCE

Work and Travel Program in the US

May 2024 - September 2024

Project Coordinator, Pasona Recruitment (Thailand)

July 2023 - Feb 2024

- Liaised with HR managers and officers from over 20 companies, scheduled and followed up on meetings
- Served as point of communication between internal and external stakeholders
- Manage project-related paperwork, quotations, invoices, receipts from more than 10 vendors, including monitoring expenses and timeline

Internship, Directorate of Intelligence, Royal Thai Air Force. June2021 - July 2021

Translated and summaried news and magazine related to military and air force

CERTIFICATES



AWS Academy Graduate - AWS Academy Data Engineering

Amazon Web Services (AWS) Issued June 2023